[Flourished Peony]
[Episode 2]
- My lady, watch your step.
- Okay.
♫ The Luo River cleanses the moonlight haze ♫
♫ Flowing into a scorching long river ♫
♫ A jade-like face not yet indulged
in mundane pleasures ♫
♫ Youth sets its own wandering path ♫
♫ Let not the secular world constrain ♫
♫ How can they guess with mundane eyes ♫
♫ Smiling as the storm stir the dust ♫
♫ Flowers should bloom proudly ♫
♫ Reflecting the color of the sky ♫
♫ Never withering ♫
♫ Do not fail the varied fragrance ♫
♫ Let not the secular world constrain ♫
♫ How can they guess with mundane eyes ♫
♫ Smiling as the storm stir the dust ♫
♫ Flowers should bloom proudly ♫
♫ Reflecting the color of the sky ♫
♫ Never withering ♫
♫ Do not fail the varied fragrance ♫
Minister Chen.
I've heard that your son
would soon go to the capital
to take the imperial examination.
My own son also wishes to participate
in this year's Provincial Examination.
Why not let them
travel to the capital together?
My son has gained
the favor of the County Princess
and is bound to be promoted.
In the future, our two families
should interact more
and support each other in official circles.
It will be beneficial.
Whoever forms an alliance with Prince Ning
will become my comrade.
The Floral Envoy accompanies
the County Princess
to relax here.
It's obvious who is the son-in-law
favored by His Highness.
I must remind you
to beware lest all your efforts be in vain.
Your Highness, we have arrived.
Greetings, Princess.
- No need for formalities.
- Thank you, Your Highness.
Your Highness.
Zishu.
Long time no see.
How have you been recently?
All is well.
I've heard about what happened.
Please don't worry too much, Your Highness.
The floral banquet is ready.
Please invite the Floral Envoy.
The Envoy is resting after the tiring journey.
Please wait a moment.
Very well, very well.
My lord, it's time to get up.
Everyone is waiting for you.
Greetings, Floral Envoy.
Greetings to everyone.
Where did you get drunk last night?
You slept all the way and made us wait.
I wanted to leave more time
for the County Princess' pleasantries.
Mr. Liu, you wouldn't blame me, right
Of course not.
The presence of the County
Princess and Floral Envoy
is honoring to my house.
Come, please.
My lady.
Your Highness, please.
Please watch your step.
This environment and these flowers
have been specially prepared
for your arrival.
Your Highness, look over there.
There are a few very rare varieties.
Come on, have a look.
It's really beautiful.
The Luoyang officialdom is
full of hidden talents.
Mr. Liu has put in great effort
to gather so many
renowned items rarely seen even in Chang'an.
My daughter-in-law is skilled
at cultivating peonies.
She can cultivate
even the most novel varieties.
Floral Envoy, if there's any you want,
you can take it home to enjoy
to your heart's content.
That's your dowry, my lady.
If they belong to the young lady.
I'll pass.
A true gentleman
does not take what others love.
Today, I wanted
to adorn my hair with fresh flowers.
But the inn was so shabby
that I couldn't find a suitable one.
But this garden full of peonies
does seem fitting.
This one, right? I see.
Hold on.
Please forgive me, Your Highness.
the peonies are flattered
by your affection.
But these peonies
are the dowry given by my father and mother.
Even if I am dull,
I dare not be unfilial.
I hope Your Highness can show mercy.
Whether you are filial or not
is of no consequence to me.
Youzhen.
Since it is her dowry, let it be.
Zishu, it's just a flower.
Can't you bear to part with it?
But…
As the daughter of the imperial family,
you must have seen all the rare things.
To be honest,
these peonies
are just ordinary flowers
in your eyes, Your Highness.
But to me,
they are of considerable value
to carry with oneself.
I hope you can show leniency.
Why bother quibbling with a woman
of no significance like me?
After all is said and done,
it's all about money.
Indeed.
Peonies are flowers in our eyes.
But in the eyes of merchants,
they are nuggets of gold.
That's true, Your Highness.
As long as we take the branches of these
flowers, plant them in the soil,
and tend to them diligently,
next Spring, they will bloom,
one flower becoming two.
They're more than just nuggets of gold.
They're practically a wealth-bringing
deity that generates money annually.
Enough.
My wife is a vulgar huckster
and has offended the County Princess.
Your Highness,
please don't stoop to her level.
The County Princess is naturally beautiful.
Even without fresh flowers adorning her,
her grace stands out.
Other vulgar powders and
rogue creams in the garden
cannot hold a candle to her.
Let it be.
Let's leave these nuggets of gold
to the young lady.
I am magnanimous.
So be it.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Your Highness.
Allow me to take you to the Water Jade
Pavilion for a rest. This way, please.
Your Highness.
To do as one says,
I've come to help you
get rid of the troublemakers.
Do you want the 100-set way
or the 80-set way?
I won't let go of even a single flower.
I am very stingy.
So how can I afford to summon the Floral Envoy?
Moreover,
my own troublemakers
should rightfully be dealt with by myself.
No need to trouble you.
Floral Envoy.
Keeper Chen.
Long time no see.
You are as dashing and suave as ever.
The Liu Mansion has never
been this lively before.
Look at the lady of the house
with that sycophantic look,
they even mock you for being vulgar.
Where are they any better?
If I don't pretend to be
greedy for money,
how could the County Princess have
so easily given up just now?
These peonies
are the keepsakes my mother left me.
I must protect them.
What does it matter
if people disdain me a little?
Are you here for the flowers?
There are more over there.
How brazen.
Don't say that. These are
the young lady's golden goose.
The County Princess looks at
the lord with deep affection.
She must have old feelings for him.
That's why she deliberately made
things difficult for you, my lady.
It doesn't matter.
If Liu Chang and the County Princess
wish to rekindle their past relationship,
they certainly won't make room for me.
If he initiates the divorce,
it would be the Liu family breaking
the marriage contract first.
I have no reason not to agree.
To me,
this may be a good opportunity.
But once divorced,
others will regard you as a cast-off wife.
Arranging another marriage later on might be…
Silly Yulu.
Life
is yours to live.
Why bother about others' views?
These two are the daughters of Commandant Wang.
Heye, Hehua.
Greet the Floral Envoy.
I've always thought
that corrupt officials are either fat-headed
or weasel-faced.
I've never expected the Floral Envoy
to be so dashing and handsome.
Look at those unmarried ladies.
Their eyes are practically glued to him.
Common folks
tending to their own plot of land
are seen as vulgar and coarse
in their eyes.
While the officials insatiably greedy
who accept bribes
are the best marriage material
and the ladder to climb up the ranks
in their eyes.
The Current Officialdom
is becoming more and more miasmic.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Noon has arrived.
Please take your seats.
Please.
Mr. Chen, apologies
for the imperfect hospitality.
This is a small token of my feelings.
Come, please.
Mr. Chen.
Please.
- After you.
- Please.
Your Highness, please.
Please take the upper seat.
The County Princess
actually took the seat
of the Liu family's young lady.
Isn't this openly slapping Madam He's face?
The County Princess, recently widowed,
went nowhere
but Luoyang.
This Mr. Liu
is a minor judge today,
but in the future, he might just be
transferred to the capital and rise rapidly.
Your Highness, this is not proper etiquette.
Zishu, it has been a long time since I saw you.
I don't want to be too far from you.
Please, sit down.
My lady, shall we…
It's alright.
There are seats over there, let's go.
This garden is full of peonies.
There's no place for the Albizia flower.
No flowers, no fruit.
It does match.
Zishu, sit down.
Okay.
This family of troublemakers
is truly interesting.
This wine is good.
Chuanyu.
My lord.
How is this dance compared to the Pear Garden
in the palace?
Naturally, it can't compete.
But it is quite presentable.
It's more than just presentable.
The look in the eyes and the posture
of holding an umbrella
clearly have a familiar
murderous aura
of martial artists.
Youzhen, be careful.
Protect the County Princess.
My lady, get up quickly.
Quickly.
Go.
Don't move.
Treacherous official Jiang,
you let the emperor indulge in pleasure,
bringing chaos to the court hierarchy.
The Integrity Society is here
to act for heaven.
Overestimating one's own ability.
Does the Floral Envoy know kung fu?
I've never heard of it.
This is an imperial sword
bestowed by His Majesty.
When the sharp blade is unsheathed,
it's as if His Majesty has arrived in person.
What are you waiting for?
Protect the royal sword.
Be careful.
Don't splatter blood everywhere.
Staining the beautiful garments of the ladies
would be a pity.
Be careful, Yulu.
Don't cut my flowers. Fight over there.
My lady.
My lady, you scared me.
How could you just charge out like that?
I was scared.
I thought they had cut my flowers.
- Are you alright?
- I'm fine, are you?
- I'm okay.
- Control your strength well.
Do not harm the flowers.
The gold nuggets of the young Lady Liu
are too expensive to compensate.
He was previously acting as a ghost
inside the Fuyun Temple.
And now he fully reveals
the posture of someone borrowing power.
This favored one by His Majesty
is indeed not ordinary.
Kneel.
It was due to my negligence
in checking identities thoroughly
that the thieves mixed into the assembly.
Fortunately, the County Princess
was not injured.
But still, it disturbed the elegant interest
of the County Princess and the Floral Envoy.
Please forgive me.
The Liu family failed to inspect
and startled the County Princess
and the Floral Envoy.
Please show great magnanimity
and deal with it leniently.
Zishu, what are you doing?
Get up quickly.
Get up.
For the sake of you,
I won't pursue it.
What do you say, Floral Envoy?
Forget it.
This matter can't really be blamed on Lord Liu.
You…
It was just a matter of poor luck.
If today the one receiving us
was the Keeper Chen,
there would still be such a commotion.
Assaults, assassination attempts.
It happens several times each month.
I'm already used to it.
Look how skilled my subordinates are.
Mr. Liu, no need to take it to heart.
Everyone, get up.
Thank you for your clemency,
Your Highness, Floral Envoy.
Having committed many evils,
he has invited pursuit and killing.
He doesn't take it as a warning,
and yet, he's proud of it.
You have broad minds.
I am ashamed for not measuring up.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Didn't you change the way
of addressing me just now?
Why are you reverting to it again?
I still prefer you to call me by my name.
Youzhen, it's chaos here.
Let's go admire the flowers somewhere else
so that the servants tidying up
won't bother you.
- Okay.
- Please.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Thank you for coming.
Please forgive me for my poor hospitality.
Mr. Liu.
You are humble.
In today's floral banquet,
the peonies are dazzling.
We
were honored to feast our eyes
in the light of the County Princess
and the Floral Envoy.
The County Princess and the Floral
Envoy are staying here.
It will certainly lead to many banquets
and feasts in the future.
Our two families
must interact with each other more frequently.
Of course.
Floral Envoy.
This banquet cannot continue.
I shall take my leave first.
Everyone, please hold on.
Now that the assassin has been captured,
where is everyone going?
Let's continue drinking
and the entertainment.
That's the proper thing to do.
Exactly, exactly.
I will summon people to clean up immediately.
- Servants.
- No need for that.
Leave it to my men.
They are experienced.
Chuanyu.
Yes.
You know what to do.
- Take the assassin away. Tidy up the scene.
- Yes.
Aren't all corrupt officials afraid of death?
Even so, the Floral Envoy still has the mood
to continue feasting.
One who is shameless never
worries about anything.
- Shameless Jiang.
- Kneel properly.
Ladies and gentlemen, please.
Please move to the garden.
This way, please.
Seeing how proficient these subordinates are,
I can't help but want to shout 'bravo'.
Although I don't mind assassination,
before I came,
His Majesty specifically instructed me
to see if Luoyang
is as outstanding and spiritually
vibrant as the rumors say.
How should I report
today's events to His Majesty
when I return to Chang'an?
I…
Mr. Liu, there's no need for this.
I don't need your courtesies.
Well, Floral Envoy,
how much tangible courtesy
can exempt one from the crime of negligence?
This crime
can be big or small,
depending on how fast
my returning carriage goes.
I am a forgetful person.
If the journey back is long enough,
by the time I return to Chang'an,
I will have forgotten everything.
Then, His Majesty will only know that Luoyang
is warm with flowers blooming
and the common folk prospering.
The gifts for His Majesty
and the Floral Envoy
will be enough to make it difficult
for the horses to take a step.
Please rest assured.
Mr. Liu is a clear-headed person.
In the future, you will certainly
rise rapidly through the ranks.
Thank you, Floral Envoy.
Having had plenty of wine and food,
why not play something
to stretch our limbs a bit?
I remember that Zishu is quite fond of archery.
Do you have a target for archery?
Yes, yes.
County Princess, please.
Please.
Mudan, go prepare some refreshments.
- After you, Suizhi.
- Please.
How did it go off-target?
Jiang.
A gust of spring breeze just came by.
Although it messed up your aim,
it is a good omen of success
in the spring breeze.
Jiang.
Joyous events are approaching.
You have such sayings in Luoyang.
Well…
No competing for the colors of spring,
in autumn, it shall ascend
into the cloud-filled skies.
Floral Envoy.
This truly is a great omen of good fortune.
- That's right.
- Well said, well said.
Great fortune, great fortune.
Great fortune, oh great fortune.
Archery is uninteresting.
Better to switch to pitching pots, huh?
- Alright.
- Pitching pots.
Right, right.
Pitching pots, pitching pots is good.
Let's all go to the garden to pitch pots.
County Princess, please.
- Let's go.
- Please, please, please.
After you.
- Jiang.
- You go ahead.
Why does this person
deliberately hide his abilities?
And why did he aim solely
at this wealth-attracting copper coin?
A small token of appreciation.
- Thank you.
- Take care, take care.
Mr. Li, here you go.
Thank you.
Mrs. Zhang, please take care on your way.
- Thank you.
- See you again.
Thank you.
I just ran into that lad at the second gate
and found out
that those carriages brought
by the Floral Envoy
were all empty.
Those carriages were personally
bestowed by His Majesty,
representing the supreme
honor and favor of His Majesty.
And the rule of the Floral Envoy is
to travel with empty carriages
and return fully loaded.
Indeed, he is the number
one greedy official in the world.
The Floral Envoy is unfathomable,
and not as simple as he appears.
Let's not interfere with this matter.
The most important thing is to go
and find the lady of the house
to move the peonies back
to my courtyard as soon as possible.
Only then can I be at ease.
But it's impossible for Mudan to raise
so much money all at once.
And there is no way to get it from home.
It seems
that the only option is to sell
the imperial-granted Zixi pills
in order to raise the funds.
The tribute medicine can save lives
when the time comes.
They can never be sold.
When He entered the family,
didn't her father give us a large sum of money?
Now it's all spent.
How have you been managing the household?
My Lord.
Two distinguished guests have come.
Not to mention the expenses
of the banquet hosted for them,
they are going to stay here for a while.
Even if we had a gold mine,
it would not be enough.
Women simply
lack foresight.
The future career prospects of our son
and the Liu family's reputation
all depend on these few days.
But right now…
Didn't someone make an offer
on He's dowry,
those few shops?
Have Xiangfu take the accountant
and sell them.
It should tide us over for a while.
Don't even think about touching
the tribute medicine.
We must not let He discover
that what we gave back then was a forgery.
If her father gets wind of it,
it will be difficult to ask him for money
to grease the wheels in the future.
Don't act impulsively.
Let's go back first.
Let's go back,
I thought…
I thought Mother was too ill.
Even with the expensive Zixi pills,
it didn't turn the tide.
But I never expected…
I never expected the pills to be fake.
Why did they deceive me?
Why?
I clearly could have had more time.
I could have more time
to look for other miraculous medicines.
My lady.
My lady, don't be like this, my lady.
It's all because of my incompetence.
If I had discovered earlier
that the Zixi pills were fake,
I could have wasted no time
in seeking medical advice.
Mother…
Mother might have been saved.
She wouldn't have left me.
I was foolish, I was too foolish.
Don't be like this, my lady.
Don't be like this.
My lady.
The Master has been selling
medicine for so many years,
but he's never seen a real Zixi pill.
The fake medicine and the one
described in the medical books
smell and appear exactly the same.
Furthermore, as soon as Madam took it,
there indeed was some improvement.
It's only natural that you didn't notice.
It's the Liu family to blame,
not you, my lady.
My lady,
if Madam sees you
this heartbroken and self-reproaching,
she will definitely be heartbroken.
That's right.
I shouldn't torment myself for such a family.
Their lies have delayed
the treatment period for Mother.
I will certainly make them
pay the price.
But we are weak and alone.
How can we fight against them?
If we confront them now,
they will surely deny everything.
How about…
How about we tell
the Master about this
to seek justice?
No.
We have no evidence now.
Even if we involve Father,
it would be of no help.
Even if we turn Liu's house upside down
and find the real tribute medicine,
they will not admit it.
When that happens and the families fall out,
we of the He family, being mere merchants,
might bear the stigma
of being ungrateful and treacherous.
What we can do now
is to withdraw from the Liu family intact.
Once we get home,
we'll plan our next step.
In any case,
I cannot stay a moment longer
at this place of cruelty.
My lady, you want a divorce.
That's right.
Liu Shen insisted on me
marrying into the Liu family
for my birth characters.
He will surely not let me go easily.
Tomorrow the Liu family will accompany
the County Princess on a trip.
We can take this opportunity
to take back the dowry shops.
We must not let them sell them at will.
My lady.
Liu Shen does not want to let me leave.
But the County Princess and Liu Chang
can't wait for me to disappear.
Yulu, pass the message for me.
Why did you
call me here?
Everyone thinks
that peonies are exclusive to the nobility.
But they forget
that they originate
from the mountains and forests
and once bloomed
and withered away freely.
The flowers before us
are the fine specimens
gathered by Mother while accompanying
Father on his business trips
traveling across all regions.
Mother brought them to me
and taught me how to cultivate them with care.
Without my mother,
there wouldn't be the grand spectacle
that made the County Princess
and the Floral Envoy
praise unanimously.
Did you call me here just to tell me
how precious these beloved
golden nuggets of yours are,
how rare they are,
and how magnificent you were
at today's floral banquet?
If you wish to bestow a reward,
you may say so directly.
For the sake of these flowers,
as long as it's not too excessive,
I can agree to it.
I want a divorce.
What did you say?
I said,
I want a divorce.
What nonsense are you talking about?
Is it because of me and the County Princess?
My relationship with Youzhen…
That's right.
You and the County Princess
are mutually in love,
a match made in heaven.
While my status is humble,
detrimental to your reputation, so,
I am willing to leave the Liu family
to make your relationship possible.
You speak so many self-deprecating words
to grant yourself a favor, don't you?
Indeed.
Merchants value profit over righteousness.
Don't forget
that it was the He family
who came asking for medicine.
And now that the benefits are exhausted,
you think of breaking the agreement.
Our marriage began
all because of a sorcerer's words.
Even if there's no commiseration,
you should understand the other's helplessness.
Since you're weary of me
and this marriage arrangement,
why not let me leave?
This way, you'll also be free.
I disagree.
Why?
Isn't this what you've always wanted?
What I want
is not for you to decide.
You married into the Liu family.
Where you go and what you do
is all decided by me, your husband.
I have not yet said I will divorce you.
On what grounds do you
bring up divorce with me?
Matters of divorce
won't be my initiative.
You can submit documents to the authorities.
In the eyes of the public,
it will be you getting rid of me.
In your eyes, do I care that much
about how those unrelated people
see me, is that it?
- Liu Chang.
- What I truly care about
is whether my marriage stays or ends
is all up to me.
Others have no right to manipulate me,
let alone you.
He Weifang, listen well to me.
Although our marriage lacks substance,
the name of it
is not for you to just discard.
Unless I divorce you,
otherwise, don't think of leaving this place.
♫ In endless Chang'an,
the zither's melody distant ♫
♫ Plum and willow trees bask in the sunshine,
as splendor returns with the year ♫
♫ Copper palace battlements,
songs and dances, glass goblets ♫
♫ Idle clouds and duckweed,
a thousand flowers burst forth ♫
♫ Time passes gracefully,
affairs settle like fading smoke ♫
♫ Let the years go by,
carried by the wind to early desires ♫
♫ If the heart is like water,
the bloom is ever-present ♫
♫ Still cherish the moon of my hometown,
to meet for long ♫
♫ The distant night sky strewn with stars,
reflecting the lovely moon ♫
♫ The peony's magnificent beauty
fills the fragrant garden ♫
♫ With a heart as my lantern,
I don't mind the distant mountain paths ♫
♫ The flute's sound,
a fleeting life's wishes fulfilled ♫
♫ Time passes gracefully,
affairs settle like fading smoke ♫
♫ Let the years go by,
carried by the wind to early desires ♫
♫ If the heart is like water,
the bloom is ever-present ♫
♫ Still cherish the moon of my hometown,
to meet for long ♫